Khalel Corona

Oxnard, California, United States

coronakhalel@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/khalel-corona

Summary

After receiving an associate degree on the Dean's List by the age of 17, I volunteered for 2 years in another country, speaking multiple languages as a teacher to refugees from around the world. Thereafter, I received my BS with a 3.9+GPA from the #20 university on Wall Street Journal's Best Colleges in the US, receiving multiple scholarships for academic excellence. I have conducted multiple research projects leveraging enormous data and a variety of data science software for the purpose of data wrangling, data visualization, statistical data analysis, and machine learning. Having supplemented my technical skills with an effective minor in both business and philosophy, coupled with years of teaching and project management, I have also greatly refined the priceless skills of communication, critical thinking, and leadership.

Experience

kubrīčk Data Consultant

Kubrick Group

Sep 2023 - Present (7 months)

- Derive business insights and data products from diverse data using SQL, Python, Tableau, Azure DataBricks, and other business tools
- Assume Product Owner and Project Management responsibilities, emphasizing requirements engineering, agile delivery, and stakeholder management
- Work on real client projects ranging from analysis of bank account financial crime to business process optimization and database construction

BYU Econometrician

Brigham Young University

Apr 2021 - Apr 2023 (2 years 1 month)

- Led econometric research using multiple regression techniques to discover the effect of US state mask mandates on the decay of new covid case rates
- Created an ML algorithm with test accuracy of over 99% that predicted the death toll of COVID
- Study and apply statistical research design and hypothesis testing, data analysis and visualization, as well as machine learning and causal inference

BYU Economics Teaching Assistant

Brigham Young University

Aug 2022 - Jan 2023 (6 months)

- Assist a class of 500 students in comprehending fundamental economic principles and theories in the real world, increasing multiple student's test scores by over 25% and overall grade by over 10%
- Assess over 300 academic essays for comprehensive analysis upon economic phenomena and theory

BYU Economics Research Assistant

Brigham Young University

May 2022 - Aug 2022 (4 months)

- Extracted, transform, and load data (ETL) from dozens of historical archives for a Stanford University research project aimed to quantify the relationship between social mobility and education
- Produce over 5,000 data for training a genealogy machine learning algorithm, the algorithm that enabled African-Americans to have pedigrees that are more connected than white Americans, for the first time in history

Volunteer

Non-Profit Organization

Nov 2018 - Nov 2020 (2 years 1 month)

- •Create spreadsheets to analyze personas, approaches, and presentations that were most effective at student acquisition and retention
- Construct a contacting algorithm that increased our organization's teaching pool by over 15%
- · Leverage communication and interpersonal skills for unifying a teaching group of up to 8 members
- Lead weekly team building meetings for setting challenging goals, creating defined plans, reporting progress, and building morale through nuanced discussions

Education

BYU Brigham Young University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Economics (emphases: econometrics, business, and philosophy)

Apr 2021 - Apr 2023

Skills

```
Machine Learning • Interpersonal Skills • Communication • Critical Thinking • Agile Methodologies • Azure Databricks • Causal Inference • Python (Programming Language) • SQL • Tableau
```

Honors & Awards

Multicultural Scholarship - Student Life-Multicultural Apr 2022

Floyd & Dorothy Haymore - Student Life-Multicultural

Apr 2021

Walter U. Fuhriman - College of Family, Home, & Social Sciences-Economics Jan 2023

Alvina Soffel Barrett - Financial Aid Office

Aug 2022

Quinn Scholarship - College of Family, Home, & Social Sciences-Economics Aug 2022